Guide to the Robert T. Jones Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
- Violins and Acoustics, Series V
  - Violin article [Acoustic experiments with the violin] (Box 33, Folder 6)
  - Violin article [Acoustic experiments with the violin] (for Catgut Accoustical Society) (Box 33, Folder 7)
  - Violin makers (Box 33, Folder 8)
  - Violin measurements (Box 33, Folder 9)
  - Violin sources - Pickering (Box 33, Folder 10)
  - Violin sources - Schelleng (Box 33, Folder 11)
  - Violin sources - various (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Violin test program (Box 33, Folder 13)
  - Violins - correspondence and assorted materials, 1967-96 (Box 33, Folder 14)
  - Violins - GW and other tests (Box 33, Folder 15)
- General Files, Series VI
  The General Files include biographical and bibliographic materials; correspondence; subject files on scientific topics, the Vietnam War, peace activities, his research on Max Munk, and other topics; and photographs of Jones. Within this series there may be some materials that pertain to aeronautics, optics, and acoustics.
  - Addresses (personal and professional) (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Addresses (professional colleagues) (Box 34, Folder 2)
  - Ames Fellows, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 3)
  - Ames Fellows Dinner, 1986 (Box 34, Folder 4)
  - Ames, misc., 1970 (Box 34, Folder 5)
  - Artificial heart (Box 34, Folder 6)
  - Automation, facts and figures (Box 34, Folder 7)
  - Award certificates (Box 34, Folder 8)
  - Awards, correspondence, programs, clippings, 1976-90 (Box 34, Folder 9)
  - Awards - photographs (Box 34, Folder 10)
  - Bibliography (Box 34, Folder 11)
  - Biographical entries for Who's Who publications (Box 34, Folder 12)
  - Biography (Box 34, Folder 13)
  - Biography - Early career data (Box 34, Folder 14)
  - Book reviews (Box 34, Folder 15)
  - Buseman, Adolf - memorial tribute (Box 35, Folder 1)
  - Byrd, Paul F. - loyalty reference (Box 35, Folder 2)
  - Circuits and IC's (Box 35, Folder 3)
  - Civil Service records (Box 35, Folder 4)
  - Clippings (arms race, US-Soviet relations), 1977-80 (Box 35, Folder 5)
  - Clippings - Vietnam war and other subjects (Box 35, Folder 6)
  - Clippings - peace (Box 35, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, A-C (Box 35, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, D-G (Box 35, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, H-L (Box 35, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence, M-O (Box 35, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, P-R (Box 35, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence, S-T (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence, V-W (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence, no last name, fragment, and miscellaneous (Box 35, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence, misc. - seems to be related to NASA / governmental issues?, 1940s-50s (Box 35, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, Letters out and drafts of letters (Box 35, Folder 17)
  - deSilva, Brian - correspondence (Box 36, Folder 1)
  - DeWitt, Hugh and Livermore, 1986 (Box 36, Folder 2)
  - Electric auto (Box 36, Folder 3)
  - Electromechanical data - magnets (Box 36, Folder 4)
  - Electronics, miscellaneous (Box 36, Folder 5)
  - Engines (Box 36, Folder 6)
  - European trip, 1955 (Box 36, Folder 7)
  - External combustion engine - paper and notes (Box 36, Folder 8)
  - Galilean relativity (Box 36, Folder 9)
  - GHD [gravity] (Box 36, Folder 10)
  - Heppenheimer, T. A. - book comments, 1995 (Box 36, Folder 11)
  - Honorary degree, Univ. of Colorado, 1971 (Box 36, Folder 12)
  - Idea of Progress - sources (1) (Box 36, Folder 13)
  - Idea of Progress - sources (2) (Box 36, Folder 14)
  - Idea of Progress - text, correspondence, misc. (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Idea of Progress - illustrations and figures (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Image sharpening: holography (Box 37, Folder 3)
  - Japan - commercial (Box 37, Folder 4)
  - Japan - commercial, contract (Box 37, Folder 5)
  - Jones, "Star Wars and the One Megaton Truck" (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Kite (Great Boston Kite Festival), 1972 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Laser ranging (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Letters of recommendation for RTJ and personnel matters, 1933-48 (Box 37, Folder 9)
  - Letters published, 1967-86 (Box 37, Folder 10)
  - Letters to editors, 1967-83 (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Loyalty hearings, 1950-79 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Macon High School, 1976, 1984 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Macon, Miss. - newspapers, 1942-1983 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Mark, Hans (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Munk, M. - AIAA nomination of, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 16)
  - Munk, Max - correspondence and tribute (Box 37, Folder 17)
  - Munk, Max - sources (1) (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Munk, Max - sources (2) (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - NAS Award in Aerodynamic Engineering (with photographs), 1990 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - NAS resolution on Nuclear War and Pope's statement on role of the scientist in working for world peace (Box 38, Folder 4)
  - NASA Eng. Colloquium poster for Jone's talk, 1974 (Box 38, Folder 5)
  - Oscilloscopes (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Personal data (Box 38, Folder 7)
  - Photographs - aviation history (Box 38, Folder 8)
  - Photographs - NACA groups, 1948-58 and undated (Box 38, Folder 9)
  - Photographs - R. T. Jones (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - Photos and postcards, miscellaneous (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Portrait Ceremony, 1983 (Box 38, Folder 12)
  - Publicity - R. T. Jones, clippings, 1972-90 (Box 38, Folder 13)
  - Reference data, misc. (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Ronchi test (Box 38, Folder 15)
  - Sakharov, etc. (mostly clippings and articles) (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Santa Clara County - airport, miscellaneous (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Science, misc. clippings (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Seminars, 1963-77 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Senators and Congressmen, clippings (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - SETI (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Slides (7) and Nuclear War Graphics Package Slide Descriptions (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Sociology (assorted clips on issues) (Box 39, Folder 8)
  - Space Science - Some Selected Problems and Accomplishments, Foothill College lecture, 1960 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Stirling engine (1) (Box 39, Folder 10)
  - Stirling engine (2) (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Transistors (Box 39, Folder 12)
  - Tsien, Hsue-shen (articles about and letters from Iris Chang), 1992 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Tube characteristics V.T.V.M. (Box 39, Folder 14)
  - Turner, Nura D., articles and correspondence, 1967-89 (Box 39, Folder 15)
  - Vietnam: anti-war letters out, 1967-68 (Box 39, Folder 16)
  - Vietnam War: Letters received, 1967-70 (Box 39, Folder 17)
  - Vietnam: anti-war literature (Box 39, Folder 18)
  - Vietnam Summer Community Organizing Project (Cambridge, MA), 1967 (Box 39, Folder 19)
- Videocassettes, Series VII
  - Oblique wing flutter model flight tests, Steve Morris[?], Stanford, Oct. 25, 1989 (Box 40)
  - Active Control Flying Wing Project. Palo Alto Shipping Company. (Box 40)
  - High Tech Heroes (copyright 1990 Cybernetic Arts). Episodes 12, 6, 2, 10 (sample) (Box 40)
  - Unlabelled [did not view for content] (Box 40)
  - Unlabelled [did not view for content] (Box 40)
- Oversize Materials, Series VIII
  - Macon County Historical Society, "Our Heritage Past and Present 1776-1976" (Box 41, Folder 1)
  - Clipping (on oblique wing plane by R. T. Jones), circa 1972 (Box 41, Folder 2)
  - Antisymmetric model - drawings, 1971 (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Patent 3,737,121 (Dual-Fuselage Aircraft) (Box 41, Folder 4)
  - Patent 3,971,535 (Oblique-wing Supersonic Aircraft), 1976 (Box 41, Folder 5)
- Additional Materials, Series IX
  - Notebook on violin research, 1972 (Box 43, Folder 1)
  - Notebook on violin research, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 2)
  - Notebook on violin research, 1973 (Box 43, Folder 3)
  - Notebook on aerodynamics and other subjects, n.d. (Box 43, Folder 4)
  - Computer typescript for Wing Theory, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 5)
  - Published version of Wing Theory [still in plastic wrap] (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Smithsonian Physical Tables, 8th edition, with lengthy inscription to Jones by David J. Lewis, 1942 (Box 44, Folder 2)
  - Classical Aerodynamic Theory, compiled by R. T. Jones; NASA Reference Publication 1050 (Box 44, Folder 3)
  - History of Macon R-1 Sports, taken from Lee McDowell's Collection [1899-1976] (Box 44, Folder 4)
  - Items found in Jones'books: note from H.K., 1991, and page of notes on violins (Box 44, Folder 5)